Historical Audiovisual Collection, 1912-2012 (bulk 1945-1996 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 6: Public Talks, 1945-2010; 693 items
  - Interviews, 1956-2005 January 6; 110 items
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Jim Knowlton 1900, 1982; 297; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Harold Medina 1909 - first group of Joe Boyda - Woodrow and (?) from Montclair, 1982; 298; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Don Griffin '23, 1982; 299; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Laughlin (Ledlie), 1982; 300; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Charlie Rogers '09, 1982; 301; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Carl Erdman '19, 1982; 302; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Dodds (WWSPIA), 1982; 303; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Gregg Dougherty '17, 1982; 304; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Harold Dodds - overview, 1982; 305; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 56)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - Ed Gemmel '34 (Former Admissions V.P.), 1982; 306; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 57)
    - Dennis Sullivan Interviews - C.W. Edwards'36 (Former Admissions Director), 1982; 307; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 57)
    - W. Robert Connor - Director, Council of the Humanities, circa 1983; AR.2001.067; 1451; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 34)
      unedited raw footage. VHS; Duration: 7 mins.
    - P.U. Campus Footage - Bowen Interview, 1984; AR.2001.063; 1278; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour - William G. Bowen interview, 1985; AR.2001.067; 1542; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 103)
    - President Harold Shapiro - press conference at Nassau Hall, 1987; AR.2001.067; 1540; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 103)
    - Brooke Shields '87 - reporters questioning her at Commencement 1987, AR.2001.067; 1561; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
    - W. Arthur Lewis, 1988; AR.2001.063; 1284; 2 Videocassette(s) (Box 21)
    - Interview with Lyman Spitzer, Princeton Plasma Physics Laboratory Founder, 1988; AR.2006.037; 2115; 1 Disc(s) (Box 209)
    - President Harold Shapiro, circa 1988; AR.2001.067; 1554; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
    - Joan Stack Interview with Bill McCleery, 1991; AR.2004.040; 2093; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
    - Joan Stack Interview with Bill McCleery, 1991; AR.2004.040; 2093; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
    - Paul Edwards, 1992; AR.2005.105; 2278; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
      Transfer from video. Compact cassette.
    - James Wei, 1992; AR.2005.105; 2282; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
    - George Schultz '42 and Alexander Bessmertnykh -- "A Retrospective on the End of the Cold War", 1993; 2136; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
      interview conducted by Daniel Schorr, broadcast on NPR on 2/26. Conference held at Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs from 2/25-2/27. Compact cassette.
    - John Hlafter, 1993; 2146; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      McMillan Hall. Compact cassette.
    - Harold Shapiro, 1993; AR.2005.105; 2283; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
      A side labeled "HTS," B side labeled "Shiozuka". Compact cassette.
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Day 1994 - Awards Ceremony, AR.2001.067; 1458; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 35)
    - Jeremiah Finch, 1994; 2143; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - D.C. Orange and Black Reception -- Simon Levine, 1994; AR.2005.105; 2280; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
    - Harriet Durman, New Jersey Commisioner of Community Affairs - State of the State, 1995; AR.2001.067; 1423; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 31)
      Created by Cable Television Network of New Jersey. VHS.
    - Gordon Wu '58 - featued on CNN Pinnacle, 1995; AR.2001.067; 1448; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 34)
      Created by Advertising Information Services. VHS; Duration: 30 mins.
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Mark Wiranowski, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1927; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
      Transcript in Historical Subject File. Created by Peter Rowinsky. Compact cassette.
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Polly Breyer, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1928; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Graig Foster, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1929; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Dennis Chao, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1930; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Molly Graves, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1931; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Chris Kimberly, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1932; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Mark Thompson, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1933; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Garret Anderson, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1934; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Kristin Fountain, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1935; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 114)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Pete Schwartz, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1936; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 114)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Randi Cohen, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1937; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 114)
    - Student Interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian Co-op, Dean Silverman, 1995; AR.1995.102; 1938; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 114)
    - John Bonner -- Biology 1947, 1995; 2139; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 217)
      Copy. Compact cassette.
    - John Bonner -- Biology 1947, 1995; 2139; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - Edward Sullivan -- Dean of the College 1966 - 1972, 1995; 2140; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - Richard Lester, 1995; 2141; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - Lyman Spitzer, Jr. -- Astrophysics, 1995; 2145; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - A. Walton Litz '47, 1995; 2147; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      English department chair (1975-1981). Compact cassette.
    - Charles Gillespie -- History and History of Science (1947-1987), 1995; 2148; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
    - Walter Johnson, 1995; 2149; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      20 McCosh -- June or July? 12, 1995. 2 copies. Compact cassette.
    - Ruth Simmons, 1995; 2150; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      Vice Provost?. Compact cassette.
    - Jeremiah Finch -- Dean of the College 1955 - 1961, 1995; 2154; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
    - Seymour Bogdonoff -- Aeronautical Engineer, 1995; 2155; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
    - Prof. Michael Danielson, 1995; 2156; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      Dept. of Politics + Woodrow Wilson School since 1963, Member of Patterson Committee on Co-education. Compact cassette.
    - Henry Drewry, 1995; 2157; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      Teacher Preparation Department, Afro-American Studies 1968-1988. Compact cassette.
    - Stanley Keeley, 1995; 2159; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      in his office. Compact cassette.
    - Dick Spies, 1995; AR.2005.105; 2274; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
    - Fred Hargardon, 1995; AR.2005.105; 2289; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
      B side labeled "Martin H..(?).. Interview 12/2/94". Compact cassette.
    - Princeton's 250th Anniversary - Healy, Katherine S. - performer in The Best of Princeton Dance Concert, 1996; 1367; 2 Videocassette(s) (Box 8)
    - George Reynolds -- Prof. of Physics Emeritus, 1996; 2152; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      In his office in Jadwin Hall. Compact cassette.
    - Harold Shapiro, 1996; AR.2005.105; 2284; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
    - The Princeton Experience: Interviews with Black Alumni, 1997; 581; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 44)
    - George Kennan '25 -- Institute for Advanced Study, 1997; 2151; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
    - Toni Morrison - NBC Today show, 1998; AR.2001.067; 1468; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 36)
    - Toni Morrison - Oprah Winfrey Show - "Paradise" in Oprah's Book Club - discussion on Princeton campus, 1998; AR.2001.067; 1476; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 37)
    - Toni Morrison - Oprah Winfrey Show - "Paradise" in Oprah's Book Club - discussion on Princeton campus, 1998; AR.2001.067; 1476; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 39)
    - President Goheen, 2004 October 21; 2094; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
      Interviewed by University Archivist Dan Linke. Labeled "C-1 T-1, Copy 2". DVCAM or MiniDV.
    - President Goheen, 2004 October 26; 2095; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
    - President Goheen, 2004 November 4; 2096; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
      Interviewed by University Archivist Dan Linke. Labeled "C-1 T-3, Copy 2". DVCAM or MiniDV.
    - President Goheen, 2005 January 6; 2097; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
      Interviewed by University Archivist Dan Linke. Labeled "C-1 T-4, Copy 2". DVCAM or MiniDV.
    - Radio--FYI 3/23 and 3/24 McHugh with Shapiro, undated; 601; 1 Disc(s) (Box 212)
      WPRB RADIO. Created by Princeton Media Services. Compact disc; Duration: 30-33 min.
    - Radio--FYI 3/23 and 3/24 McHugh with Shapiro, undated; 601; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 79)
      WPRB RADIO. Created by WPRB-FM. 1/4 inch magnetic tape, 7-inch reel; Duration: 30-33 min.
    - Selection of Prof. Goheen as President: Interviews, undated; 603; 1 Disc(s) (Box 224)
      interviews with Pres. Dodds, Prof. Goheen, Dean Finch, Dean Lippincott, and Prof. Oates. Compact disc; Duration: 22 min.
    - President Harold Shapiro, undated; AR.2001.067; 1406; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 30)
      original raw footage. Created by Ambassador Resources Video Communications. VHS.
    - Gene Lowe '71 (dean of students) - SDS, ABC (Association of Black Collegians), New South sit-in, undated; AR.2001.067; 1551; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 103)
    - Nadine Gordimer, undated; AR.2001.067; 1553; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
    - "Marta Abba" - in Italian, undated; AR.2001.067; 1559; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
    - Interviews with Latino Alumni, undated; AR.2001.098; 1570; 3 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
    - Robert F. Goheen '40, *48: Reflections of a President, undated; 2025; 2 Disc(s) (Box 204)
      Has titles. 2 copies. DVD.
    - Lawrence Stone, undated; 2142; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - Prof. Norman Sollenberger, undated; 2144; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    - Sheldon Judson '40, undated; 2158; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 211)
      Geology Dept. 1955-1988, Chair of University Research Board 1972-1979. Compact cassette.
    - Paul Volcker, undated; AR.2005.105; 2281; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 215)
    - Robert F. Goheen '40, *48: Reflections of a President, undated; 2353; 2 Disc(s) (Box 204)
      No titles. 2 copies. DVD.
- Series 7: Unidentified/Unknown Content, 1948-2009; 65 items
  The Unidentified/Unknown Content series contains audiovisual materials of unknown content.
  Series is described in chronological order, where possible, with undated materials at the end of each series.
  - Miscellaneous 3 - VP Conference, 1948; AR.1997.006; 237; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Miscellaneous B, 1949; AR.1997.006; 235; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
  - Miscellaneous 2, 1949; AR.1997.006; 236; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Part 1949, AR.1997.006; 238; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Miscellaneous A, 1950; AR.1997.006; 234; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
  - 1956, 596; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 79)
    various subjects on tape. 1/4 inch magnetic tape, 7-inch reel.
  - unknown, 1964; 49; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 131)
    Created by ABC. 16 mm.
  - IDA Incidents, 1970; 1939; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 114)
  - IDA Incidents, 1970; 1939; 1 Disc(s) (Box 224)
  - Miguel Barnet, 1984; 1730; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 108)
  - D. Stires?, Ruckelshaus?, 1984; 1830; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 110)
  - Charles Issawi, 1985; 1732; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 108)
  - Ivy Club, Donald Griffin Class of 1923, 1986; 1701; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - "Students and a Teacher", 1991; AR.2005.105; 2294; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 216)
  - D. Meade/ R. Goldston, 1993; 566; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 43)
  - Princeton, 1998; AR.1998.004; 584; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 45)
    Script: Irving Jacoby and Basil Bayea '31; Photography: Peter Glushanok; Cast: Eugene Buttle '49, Richard Markus '49, David Trimble '47, Ralph Woodward '51. Created by Ralph Woodward '51. VHS; Duration: 32 minutes.
  - "Princeton 6" - 3/29/2001, 1581; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 7)
    Created by Henniger Arlington. Betacam SP; Duration: 32 min.
  - unknown, undated; 12; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Three in the Afternoon, undated; 40; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
    Created by Rombex. 1 inch videotape; Duration: 30 min.
  - Three in the Afternoon, undated; 40; 3 Videocassette(s) (Box 13-15)
    3 copies, appear to be same edit. U-matic; Duration: 30 min.
  - unknown, undated; 50; 2 Film Reel(s) (Box 132)
    35 mm.
  - Explorer, undated; 52; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
    Created by US Army. 16 mm; Duration: 10 min.
  - unknown, undated; 54; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 58; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 58; 1 Disc(s) (Box 226)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 62; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 62; 1 Disc(s) (Box 226)
  - The Fleetcher Richards Co., undated; 67; 2 Film Reel(s) (Box 135)
  - unknown, undated; 69; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 42)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 190; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 164)
  - unknown, circa 2009; 190; 1 Disc(s) (Box 226)
  - Two Seniors, undated; 497; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Princeton #4, undated; 498; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Princeton #2, undated; 499; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Princeton #3, undated; 500; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Princeton #1, undated; 501; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - Princeton #5, undated; 502; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 219)
  - unknown, undated; 505; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 220)
  - unknown, undated; 507; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 220)
  - unknown, undated; 508; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 220)
  - Three in the Afternoon - re-edited 5/23, undated; 519; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 16)
    U-matic; Duration: 30 min.
  - Three in the Afternoon - re-edited 5/24, undated; 520; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 16)
  - Princeton -- Hesel Hill Roll VTR Scene 4, undated; 526; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box DVD)
  - Princeton -- Fox Roll VTR - Tower, Endings, undated; 527; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box DVD)
  - Princeton -- White VTR, undated; 529; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 19)
  - Princeton -- White VTR #2, undated; 530; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 19)
  - James Newman and Dudley Woodbridge, undated; 563; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 42)
  - unknown, undated; 605; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 80)
  - Erikson, undated; 624; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 81)
  - Robert Frost -- Record 2, undated; 650; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - Richard Morgan '58, undated; 654; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - Platt, undated; 656; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - unknown, undated; 662; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - unknown, undated; 663; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - unknown, undated; 664; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
  - unknown, undated; 745; 3 Audio Reel(s) (Box 115)
  - unknown, undated; 748; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 83)
  - unknown - Paul Bedford, undated; 749; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 83)
  - "Princeton", undated; 834; 7 Boxes? (Box *missing*)
  - Unidentified: This is America "House of Mercy", undated; 919; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 188)
  - unidentified, undated; 1342; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Esther Palmer, undated; 2134; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 203)
    Have not transcribed -- Do not copy per ??? (Challener). Compact cassette.
  - "You Asked For It", undated; AR.2005.105; 2295; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 216)